<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Composter-News &#8211; tmkhb</title>
	<atom:link href="http://tmkhb.net/category/composter-news/feed/?simply_static_page=137" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>http://www.tmkhb.net/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2023 04:10:28 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>zh-CN</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>How Composting Organic Food Waste Is Beneficial For Our Environment</title>
		<link>http://www.tmkhb.net/2023/03/19/how-composting-organic-food-waste-is-beneficial-for-our-environment/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 19 Mar 2023 04:10:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Composter-News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.tmkhb.com/?p=3421</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Composting organic food waste is a simple and effective [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Composting organic food waste is a simple and effective way to reduce the amount of waste that ends up in landfills, and to create a valuable soil amendment that can be used in gardening and agriculture. When food waste decomposes in a landfill, it produces methane, a potent greenhouse gas that contributes to climate change. Composting food waste instead, it is converted into a nutrient-rich fertilizer that can be applied to enhance the fertility and health of the soil.<br />
 <br />
One of the main benefits of composting food waste is that it reduces the number of greenhouse gases that are produced by landfills. As food waste decomposes, it releases methane and other gases into the atmosphere. These gases trap heat, contributing to global warming. When food waste is composted instead, it is broken down by microorganisms in the presence of oxygen, which produces much less methane. In addition, the carbon that is contained in food waste is sequestered in the soil, where it can be used to support plant growth.<br />
 <br />
Another benefit of composting food waste is that it produces a high-quality fertilizer that can be used to improve soil health and fertility. Compost is rich in essential plant nutrients like nitrogen, phosphorous, and potassium. It also contains microorganisms that can help to promote healthy soil structure and fertility. This makes it an excellent amendment for gardens, lawns, and farms. By composting food waste, you can reduce the need for synthetic fertilizers, this can cost a lot of money and be bad for the environment.<br />
 <br />
Furthermore, composting food waste can also help to conserve water. By improving soil structure, composting can help to increase the water-holding capacity in the soil.<br />
 <br />
This means that it takes less water to keep plants hydrated, which can be especially beneficial in areas that experience water shortages.<br />
 <br />
In conclusion, composting organic food waste is an easy and effective way to reduce the amount of waste that ends up in landfills and to create a valuable soil amendment that can be used in gardening and agriculture. It also helps in reducing the greenhouse gases that are produced by landfills, creating a high-quality fertilizer, and conserving water. It’s an easy step that can be taken to protect the environment and promote sustainable living.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Kitchen Waste Management</title>
		<link>http://www.tmkhb.net/2023/03/06/kitchen-waste-management/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 06 Mar 2023 15:00:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Composter-News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.tmkhb.com/?p=3414</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Kitchen waste management is a crucial aspect of househo [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Kitchen waste management is a crucial aspect of household waste management, as it is estimated that a large portion of household waste comes from the kitchen. If not managed properly, kitchen waste can cause environmental problems, attract pests and create unpleasant odors. Moreover, it can also lead to blockages in drainage systems and ultimately harm the environment.<br />
 <br />
There are various ways to manage kitchen waste, including composting, recycling, and proper disposal.<br />
 <br />
<strong>Composting:</strong> Composting is the process of breaking down organic matter such as food scraps, yard waste, and paper into a nutrient-rich soil amendment. Composting is an eco-friendly way to dispose of kitchen waste and it is also a cost-effective alternative to buying fertilizer. To compost the kitchen waste, one can use a compost bin, or tumbler or simply make a compost pile in the yard. The compost bin should be placed in a sunny location and should be regularly turned to ensure proper aeration.<br />
 <br />
<strong>Recycling:</strong> Another way to manage kitchen waste is by recycling. Recycling is the process of converting waste materials into new products. Common kitchen waste items that can be recycled include glass, metal, paper, and plastic. These materials can be recycled and made into new products, reducing the amount of waste in landfills. To recycle kitchen waste, one can separate recyclables from other waste materials and place them in the appropriate recycling bins.<br />
 <br />
<strong>Proper Disposal:</strong> The third and most basic way to manage kitchen waste is proper disposal. This involves throwing away waste in the appropriate trash bin. It is important to properly dispose of kitchen waste to prevent it from attracting pests and creating unpleasant odors. To properly dispose of kitchen waste, one should wrap it in a newspaper or a plastic bag before throwing it away.<br />
 <br />
In conclusion, proper kitchen waste management is essential to reduce waste and preserve the environment. Composting, recycling, and proper disposal are effective methods to manage kitchen waste. By practicing these methods, we can help reduce waste in landfills and protect the environment. In addition, we can also save money and improve the quality of the soil by composting food waste. Finally, it is important to educate ourselves and others about the importance of proper kitchen waste management and the positive impact it can have on the environment.<br />
<iframe title="TMK Organic Food Waste Composting Machine" width="500" height="281" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/lVSvQAGw0LY?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>What Are The Types Of Composting?</title>
		<link>http://www.tmkhb.net/2023/02/20/what-are-the-types-of-composting-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 20 Feb 2023 06:10:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Composter-News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.tmkhb.com/?p=3406</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[What is compost, and what are the benefits of compostin [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>What is compost, and what are the benefits of composting?</strong><br />
 <br />
Well, compost is to put just decayed organic matter, and it’s quite a wide-ranging label. Even twigs are organic matter, and so is a banana peel. When you collect some of these items and put these in a compost pile together, they break down automatically into a nutrient-rich fertilizer that later helps gardens grow.<br />
 <br />
Composting has a lot of benefits, considering it is an essential tool for farmers and gardeners. Compost speeds up water retention in soil, which means the saplings or budding plants in that soil need a lower amount of irrigation. It also helps to ease larger crop yields, giving food producers a more excellent harvest. It all adds up to even more growth without using excessive water and on top of that more affordable way to harvest food, flowers, and other plants.<br />
 <br />
<strong>What are the types of composting?</strong><br />
 <br />
<strong>There are quite a few types of composting, but generally, there are four types of composting that one should know about.</strong><br />
 <br />
<strong>On-Site Composting:</strong><br />
 <br />
By using this method of organic waste composting, you can recycle your food waste and garden waste into products for your farming and gardening needs. It is widely used at homes because on-site composting does not require sizeable-sized piles or hard techniques and requires minimal attention. On top of that, this type can also be used even when you don’t have a huge backyard or space; you just have an old bin or a container, and all your waste is ready for recycling.<br />
 <br />
<strong>Types of materials:</strong><br />
 <br />
Materials that can be used for this type is composting varies from kitchen scraps such as cooked or uncooked fruits or vegetables, eggshells of eggs from your morning pancakes, coffee ground from your morning coffee, etc. You can also use cardboard and paper too, dead leaves, and branches from your lawn, and it can all be recycled into fertilizers and other farming products. However, the combination of brown materials and green materials should be done in moderation to ensure complete decomposition.<br />
 <br />
<strong>Things to keep in mind:</strong><br />
 <br />
Since this method is for the small size of the pile, the process takes place in the compost bin itself. The food waste composting process doesn’t get affected by climatic or seasonal factors, but that doesn’t mean you don’t need to take any measures about it. You should place the bin in some corners, which should be dry and shady. Also, glass and metal waste should be taken out of the bin.<br />
 <br />
<strong>Process Time:</strong><br />
 <br />
It generally takes about a year or two to complete the process, but if you turn the pile from time to time during the procedure, the process can speed up by three to six months.<br />
 <br />
<strong>Vermicomposting:</strong><br />
 <br />
Unlike other methods, different worms are used in this method of decomposing organic matter. Worms such as earthworms, red wigglers, etc., are added to the pile, and then these worms will eat and break down these materials into fertilizers.<br />
 <br />
<strong>Types of Materials:</strong><br />
 <br />
The materials which are used in this method of composting are not very different from other types of composting. Water and oxygen are essential materials.<br />
 <br />
<strong>Things To Keep In Mind: </strong><br />
 <br />
As high heat leads to harm, to the worms, so keep in mind that high-carbon materials are encouraged. You should thoroughly moisten the layer of brown materials or green materials by adding an appropriate amount of water before adding worms in it but make sure the worms are not nightcrawlers. Keeping the temperature under 30 degrees Celsius is ideal because high temperatures might kill the worms inside the pile, so it needs to be checked regularly.<br />
 <br />
Process time – It just takes one to three months of composting all the organic materials to turn into organic fertilizer, which means this process takes less time and effort.<br />
 <br />
<strong>Windrow Composting:</strong><br />
 <br />
This composting is a large-scale composting method in farming because this method requires a large size of site where you can mix the organic materials into long and thin piles known as windrows. It is sometimes built-in shelters and aerated by the use of other cooling machines, but mostly, it is set out outside in the open.<br />
 <br />
<strong>Types of Materials:</strong><br />
 <br />
Farming wastes such as animal residues or manures and crop remaining are excellent sources of composting. Therefore, the materials are in abundance for making a windrow compost pile.<br />
 <br />
<strong>Things to keep in mind: </strong><br />
 <br />
As much as it is straightforward to build a windrow compost pile but you also need to do it properly. You should keep in mind that certain things affect the process and surroundings alike; for example – a too-thin pile might take longer than usual to finish, but a too-thick pile will release odors. So, to ensure the best quality compost and to complete the process faster, the pile should be set up within 12 feet wide and 3 feet high. Also, the manure should be shredded thinner than layers of remaining materials, and the pile should be turned from from time to time, and during the rainy season, it should be done every month. Plus, when the piles reach the temperature of 55 degrees Celsius in the core, that means the pile has reached its high peak.<br />
 <br />
Process time – It takes an average of two years to finish composting in a windrow compost, and that too depends on the thickness of the pile.<br />
 <br />
<strong>In-Vessel Composting:</strong><br />
 <br />
It is a combination of different types of composting, it is less downside than others, but it can produce a large size of compost. It isn’t as simple a process as the other types. It is done professionally by using <strong>organic waste converter machines</strong> and other electrical equipment, which eases the adjustment of temperature, aeration, and turning skills.<br />
 <br />
<strong>Types of materials: </strong><br />
 <br />
All kinds of waste, including brown materials like grass, twigs, manure, etc. as well as green materials like lawn clipping, fruit rind, etc. found in garbage bins or farming fields are a good source of in-vessel composting. Other waste that comes from industrial waste can also be collected and can be turned into compost.<br />
 <br />
<strong>Things to keep in mind:</strong><br />
 <br />
This process of composting is slightly expensive as it uses machines and some electrical equipment. All the steps in this process need to be taken care of, managed as well as appropriately studied. During this process, temperature adjustment, aeration, and the process of turning the mixture need proper attention from the experts. Also, the process of in-vessel composting requires a considerable amount of organic material for recycling, which means the waste from households is not enough.<br />
 <br />
<strong>Process Time:</strong><br />
 <br />
The process of in-vessel composting generally requires a few weeks and does not take a long time to get finished.<br />
<iframe title="TMK Fully Automatic Organic Food Waste Composting Machine" width="500" height="375" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/TNOBiDIMCQ8?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Composting for a Sustainable Future: How the Right Composter Can Make a Difference</title>
		<link>http://www.tmkhb.net/2023/02/12/composting-for-a-sustainable-future-how-the-right-composter-can-make-a-difference/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 12 Feb 2023 14:01:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Composter-News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.tmkhb.com/?p=3396</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In today’s world, we’re facing more and more environmen [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In today’s world, we’re facing more and more environmental challenges, from climate change to waste management. One of the most pressing issues is the increasing amount of waste we produce, much of which ends up in landfills where it can harm the environment and emit greenhouse gases.<br />
 <br />
However, there’s a simple solution to this problem that can help reduce waste, conserve resources, and promote a more sustainable future: composting.<br />
 <br />
Composting is the process of breaking down organic matter, such as food scraps, yard waste, and leaves, into a rich soil amendment. Not only does composting reduce the amount of waste that ends up in landfills, but it also creates a valuable resource for gardens, lawns, and agriculture.<br />
 <br />
But not all composters are created equal. The right composter can make a big difference in the success and efficiency of your composting efforts. That’s why it’s important to choose a composter that is both effective and user-friendly.<br />
 <br />
Enter the TMK Composter. This innovative composter is designed to make composting easy, efficient, and mess-free.<br />
 <br />
The TMK Composter features a unique, double-chambered design that allows for quick and efficient composting. The first chamber is used for active composting, while the second chamber collects finished compost. This system allows for constant composting, so you can add new matter to the first chamber even as the finished compost is being collected in the second.<br />
 <br />
One of the biggest advantages of the TMK Composter is its ease of use. The compact design makes it easy to set up and use, even in smaller spaces. It’s also made from durable materials that will withstand the elements, so you can enjoy fresh compost year-round.<br />
 <br />
In addition to its practical benefits, the Kwik Composter is also environmentally friendly. By composting your organic waste, you’re reducing the amount of waste that ends up in landfills. This not only reduces greenhouse gas emissions but also conserves valuable resources and saves space in landfills.<br />
 <br />
But the benefits of composting go beyond just reducing waste and conserving resources.<br />
 Composting also has a positive impact on the environment and helps promote a healthier, more sustainable world. For example:<br />
 <br />
<strong>&#8211; Improving soil health:</strong> Compost adds valuable organic matter to the soil, which helps improve soil structure, water-holding capacity, and nutrient availability. This can result in stronger, healthier plants and better yields in gardens and agriculture.<br />
<strong>&#8211; Reducing the need for chemical fertilizers:</strong> Compost provides a natural source of nutrients for plants, reducing the need for chemical fertilizers. This not only benefits the environment, but it also saves money and produces healthier, more flavorful food.<br />
<strong>&#8211; Conserving water:</strong> Compost improves soil structure, which helps soil retain moisture better. This can reduce the need for frequent watering, conserving this valuable resource.<br />
 <br />
In conclusion, composting is an easy, effective way to promote a more sustainable future and reduce our impact on the environment. And with the TMK Composter, you can enjoy the benefits of composting without any of the hassles. So why not order yours today and start composting for a sustainable future?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>TMK&#8217;s 5 Ton Composting Machine System Set Up</title>
		<link>http://www.tmkhb.net/2023/02/09/tmks-5-ton-composting-machine-system-set-up/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 09 Feb 2023 12:10:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Composter-News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.tmkhb.com/?p=3378</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[TMK Composter supplies a line of commercial composting  [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>TMK Composter supplies a line of commercial composting machines that can compost from 30kg of food waste a day, up to 1350kg of food waste a day. Apart from the line of commercial units, we also offer a large-scale composting machine set up for the Asia market.</p>
<p>Our machines, when paired with a grinder, and water squeezer, can increase the machine’s daily composting capacity. One such example is a large-scale set in Southeast Asia.<br />
 <br />
TMK-5000 composting machine is paired with four accessory pieces:<br />
 <br />
1 – Sorting Platform<br />
 <br />
2 – Oil and Water Separator<br />
 <br />
3 – Shredder<br />
 <br />
4 – Squeezer<br />
 <br />
The TMK-5000 has a daily capacity of 5000kg/day (5 tonnes). When paired with the above accessories, the machine’s capacity is increased to 8 tonnes a day.<br />
													<a href="https://www.tmkhb.com/product/waste-recycling-machine/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><br />
							<img decoding="async" width="1020" height="669" src="https://www.tmkhb.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/composting-system.jpg" alt="" loading="lazy" srcset="https://www.tmkhb.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/composting-system.jpg 1024w, https://www.tmkhb.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/composting-system-300x197.jpg 300w, https://www.tmkhb.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/composting-system-768x504.jpg 768w, https://www.tmkhb.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/composting-system-500x328.jpg 500w, https://www.tmkhb.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/composting-system-800x525.jpg 800w" sizes="(max-width: 1020px) 100vw, 1020px" />								</a><br />
		<strong>Sorting Platform</strong><br />
 <br />
Food waste is collected in waste hauling trucks and emptied onto the sorting platform. Operators remove contamination like plastics, metals, non-organic materials, and extra-large objects from the food waste. The food waste is then pushed toward the conveyor belt and into the oil and water separator.<br />
 <br />
<strong>Oil and Water Separator</strong><br />
 <br />
The oil and water separator compresses the oil and water from the food waste, to reduce the amount of moisture content within the organic waste. Through a conveyor belt system, the food waste is then moved to the shredder.<br />
 <br />
<strong>Shredder</strong><br />
 <br />
The shredder is used to pulverize food waste to reduce its surface area, thus increasing the machine’s daily composting capacity.<br />
 <br />
<strong>Squeezer</strong><br />
 <br />
Apart from small particle size, reducing the water content in the food waste is also crucial to increasing the machine’s composting capacity. The squeezer presses the food waste against a fine mesh screen to remove as much water as possible. The food waste is then transported through a conveyor belt and emptied directly into the composting machine.<br />
 <br />
Such large-scale composting systems are ideal for central food waste collection sites. The food waste is quickly composted in 24 hours, and the reduction rate is 80-90%. The compost can then be screened and used as a soil amendment.<br />
 <br />
[contact-form-7 id=&#8221;2659&#8243; title=&#8221;Inquiry&#8221;]</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>5 Reasons You Should Invest in a Waste Composting Machine</title>
		<link>http://www.tmkhb.net/2023/02/03/5-reasons-you-should-invest-in-a-waste-composting-machine/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2023 05:00:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Composter-News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.tmkhb.com/?p=3361</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[An organic waste composting machine is the solution to  [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>An <a style="color: #50b848; text-decoration: underline;" href="https://www.tmkhb.com/compost-machine/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><strong>organic waste composting machine</strong></a> is the solution to all the shortcomings of traditional composting. A waste composter machine is meant not only to be used as a garbage chute but also for treating and recycling solid and liquid waste material.<br />
 <br />
A waste composter machine works independently, giving out manure in return for the waste you add and also for recycling the solid and liquid waste. Let us read more about how it can benefit you.<br />
 <br />
<strong>5 Reasons to buy a Waste Composting Machine</strong><br />
 </p>
<ul>
<li>Fully automatic, time-saving, and composts all waste</li>
<li>No secondary pollution or need for different treatment methods</li>
<li>Highly efficient and occupies low space at less expense</li>
<li>Durable and safe with effective power systems</li>
<li>Safe for human handling with sterilization</li>
</ul>
<p><strong>Fully Automatic, Time-Saving, and Composts All Waste</strong><br />
 <br />
An organic waste compost machine is fully automatic. This saves a lot of manpower for operations. Often one person on a part-time basis is enough to handle the machine. The waste composter machine also takes fewer hours to process everything and converts all kinds of waste into high-quality manure.<br />
 <br />
There can be food waste, vegetables, eggs, fish, small bones, fruit peels, meals, and leftovers, and everything will quickly be converted into manure.<br />
 <br />
<strong>No Secondary Pollution or Need for Different Treatment Methods</strong><br />
 <br />
An organic waste compost machine does not waste water. It is a very odorless process and does not actually hold any toxic traits. This technology can compost waste for you without actually having a landfill or any other compost techniques.<br />
 <br />
<strong>Highly Efficient and Occupies Low Space at Less Expense</strong><br />
 <br />
Compared to a traditional composting method, a waste composter machine occupies less space as the machine is usually compact. In addition, the machine without a Modular Solar Dehydration System can convert 50 kgs of organic waste into 5-10 kgs of manure per day.<br />
 <br />
If it is used with the Modular Solar Dehydration System, it can convert 500 kgs of organic waste into 50-100 kgs of manure in a short span of 10 hours. All of this is at a very minimal expense as the operating cost of maintaining and running this is low.<br />
 <br />
<strong>Durable and Safe with Effective Power Systems</strong><br />
 <br />
A waste composter machine is built with a tank made of stainless steel. It has a lifespan of over 20 years and is very durable. There are also functions set in place, such as the overload function, to halt the machine during an overload to avoid spillage and any danger to the user.<br />
 <br />
Usually, the waste composter machines also come with effective systems, including indicators for power, heater, power saving, etc.<br />
 <br />
<strong>Safe for Human Handling with Sterilization</strong><br />
 <br />
An organic waste compost machine is actually relatively safe for human use, and human handling as a composting machine pasteurizes organic waste. It also processes sterilization and kills all forms of organisms like fungi, bacteria, viruses, and biohazards.<br />
 <br />
This way, the risk of contracting diseases or health issues for humans operating the machine is significantly reduced.<br />
 <br />
<strong>Conclusion</strong><br />
 <br />
A waste composter machine is one of the best investments you will make when it comes to waste management. It is better to have manure than to throw away the waste that you yourself have collected.<br />
 <br />
You can use the manure for gardening or growing vegetables or sell it away to your local farms. There are many benefits to why it is essential and beneficial for conducting waste composting. Here are the benefits of purchasing a waste composter machine as an actual investment rather than an expense.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Let’s Stop Wasting, Let’s Start Compositing</title>
		<link>http://www.tmkhb.net/2023/01/31/lets-stop-wasting-lets-start-compositing/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 13:31:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Composter-News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.tmkhb.com/?p=3352</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In recent years, the amount of waste produced by humans [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In recent years, the amount of waste produced by humans has been increasing exponentially. The increase in waste has been linked to a variety of factors, including population growth, increased consumption, and the lack of proper waste management. Although there have been some efforts to reduce the amount of waste produced, this has not been enough to counteract the growing problem. One of the solutions to this problem is composting, which has been gaining traction in recent years. Now, as the world moves towards a more sustainable future, composting is becoming an increasingly popular way to reduce waste. Composting not only helps the environment, but it can also be beneficial to gardens and soil in general. However, composting can be difficult to do on a large scale. That’s why companies like Earthcare are providing complete solutions for composting wet food waste.<br />
 <br />
TMK offers a range of organic waste converters which can be used to compost wet food waste from 2 kg to 300 metric tons per day. These converters are designed to be environmentally friendly, efficient, and easy to use. They are capable of handling a variety of organic materials, including fruits, vegetables, grains, and other food scraps.<br />
 <br />
Not only do TMK’s organic waste converters help reduce the amount of waste that goes into landfills and oceans, but they also help to create nutrient-rich compost that can be used to fertilize gardens and soil. This compost is rich in essential minerals and nutrients that plants need to thrive. And, since composting is a natural process, the compost created by TMK’s organic waste converters is free of any harmful chemicals or toxins that could be potentially harmful to plants or animals.<br />
 <br />
<strong>What is Composting?</strong><br />
 <br />
Composting is the process of recycling organic materials such as food scraps, garden waste, and paper products. Instead of being sent to landfills, these materials are broken down by microorganisms to create a nutrient-rich soil amendment known as compost. Composting is a great way to reduce the amount of waste produced, as it can divert up to 50% of organic waste from landfills. Additionally, composting can provide numerous benefits to the environment. It can reduce greenhouse gas emissions, improve water and air quality, and replenish soil nutrients.<br />
 <br />
Despite these benefits, composting is often overlooked as a waste management solution. This is due to a variety of factors, including the lack of knowledge about composting and the perceived difficulty of setting up a composting system. However, composting does not have to be difficult. There are numerous types of composting systems, ranging from simple backyard composting to complex industrial systems. Additionally, there are a variety of resources available to help individuals get started with composting, such as composting classes and composting kits.<br />
 <br />
Composting is a great way to reduce waste and benefit the environment. To encourage more people to get involved with composting, there should be more resources available to educate people about the benefits of composting and how to get started. Additionally, composting should be made more accessible by providing incentives to those who participate in composting, such as discounts on composting equipment or tax incentives. By making composting more accessible and encouraging more people to get involved, we can reduce the amount of waste produced and create a more sustainable future.<br />
 <br />
<strong>What is compost? – Compost Basics</strong><br />
 <br />
Compost is just organic matter that has decomposed; nevertheless, the term “organic matter” has a rather broad definition. Organic debris can include twigs and banana peels alike. These things naturally decompose when combined in a compost pile to produce a fertilizer that is rich in nutrients and supports the growth of gardens.<br />
 <br />
<strong>What to Compost?</strong><br />
 <br />
<strong>Types of Matter</strong><br />
Brown matter is anything dry or woody, such as twigs, branches, paper, and cardboard. There are certainly exceptions to the general rule that “brown” goods will often be naturally brown. Brown matter contains carbon, which gives the compost’s helpful bacteria energy.<br />
 <br />
Green matter is a term used to describe organic waste materials that may have recently been growing and still contain some moisture. Green matter can contain items like leftover fruit and vegetables, grass clippings, and coffee grounds, among other things.<br />
 <br />
Note – Most of the time, your green waste will provide your compost mixture with the right amount of moisture for effective decomposition, but if it is too dry, you might need to add extra water.<br />
 <br />
<strong>What Not to Compost?</strong><br />
 <br />
There are (nearly) unlimited possibilities for objects you may compost, but there are a few things you should avoid doing so if you want to end up with a compost that makes an effective and secure fertilizer (beyond the obvious, like plastic products).<br />
 <br />
<strong>Fish and Meat</strong><br />
 <br />
Animal byproducts, including meat, fish, eggs, dairy, and poultry products, are one of the largest groups. Even while you might assume it’s okay to compost certain kinds of animal waste, doing so can encourage the growth of bacteria, odor issues, and pests like rodents.<br />
 <br />
<strong>Oils, Fats, and Dairy</strong><br />
 <br />
Because they also draw pests, dairy products including milk, sour cream, yogurt, cheese, and butter shouldn’t be composted. The same holds for fats and oils.<br />
 <br />
<strong>Charcoal Ash and Coal</strong><br />
 <br />
You should carefully evaluate what you compost and the possible harm it might cause to your plants if your ultimate objective is to create a usable fertilizer for your plants. By the time you use your fertilizer, your vegetable garden may already be dead since items like coal or charcoal ash may contain compounds toxic to plants.<br />
 <br />
<strong>Amount of Black Walnut Tree Debris</strong><br />
 <br />
The toxin juglone, which is known to damage numerous plants, including peppers, potatoes, and tomatoes, is present in black walnut tree leaves and twigs.<br />
 <br />
<strong>Pesticide-Treated Plants or Wood</strong><br />
 <br />
Additionally, you should avoid trimmings from plants that have received pesticide treatment in the past.<br />
 <br />
<strong>Plants that are ill or are pest-infested</strong><br />
 <br />
Pests and pathogens can survive since a compost pile has to reach 141 to 145 degrees F for at least several days to kill fungus and bacteria, which is not practical for a residential compost bin.<br />
 <br />
<strong>Grass That Has Sprouted</strong><br />
 <br />
Unless a high temperature is reached, they can also live, and you probably don’t want to plant weeds in your subsequent crop.<br />
 <br />
<strong>Cat or Dog Excreta</strong><br />
 <br />
Pet waste contains germs and parasites that can lead to human illnesses, making compost dangerous. For instance, the bacterium that causes toxoplasmosis is found in cat faces and litter. Pregnant women should pay special attention to this condition because it can adversely harm an unborn child.<br />
 <br />
Composting is an important part of the effort to reduce the amount of waste that goes into landfills and oceans. TMK’s organic waste converters are an effective and efficient way to compost wet food waste on a large scale. They provide a complete solution for composting, from education and resources to the actual converters themselves. With TMK’s help, you can start composting and making a difference in the world.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Benefits of Waste Composting Machines &#038; Why You Should Consider Installing One</title>
		<link>http://www.tmkhb.net/2023/01/27/the-benefits-of-waste-composting-machines-why-you-should-consider-installing-one/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2023 13:50:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Composter-News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.tmkhb.com/?p=3336</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The organic waste composting machine addresses the draw [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The organic waste composting machine addresses the drawbacks of old composting methods, which were time-consuming, smelly, and took up a lot of space. There were a lot of other difficulties with the old way that also needed to be addressed. Composting machines are used to treat and recycle both solid and liquid waste. Yard trimmings, leaves, mulch, grass clippings, some paper products, and food scraps such as raw and cooked fruits, vegetables, grains, eggshells, coffee grounds, and in rare situations, even meat and dairy products are among the organic components that make up compost. Composting creates the ideal environment for beneficial microbes to thrive, allowing the decaying process to become incredibly life-giving.<br />
 <br />
Composting is a practical and straightforward technique to make a significant difference in today’s environmental, economic, and social challenges. Including this easy step in your ecologically friendly routine may go a long way toward reducing carbon emissions, regenerating soil, renewing water supplies, and ensuring future food security.<br />
 <br />
<strong>It is a self-contained system that provides consumers with the following advantages:</strong><br />
 <br />
<strong>1. It processes quickly:</strong><br />
 <br />
The machine technology requires fewer hours to complete the processing steps than traditional composting organic waste. The time saved composting organic waste may be better used in other productive endeavors, resulting in monetary savings.<br />
 <br />
<strong>2. It does not pollute the environment in any way:</strong><br />
 <br />
There is no wastewater in the machine technology. It also has no odor and does not have any harmful characteristics.<br />
 <br />
<strong>3. It is completely automated:</strong><br />
 <br />
The machine saves operational manpower because it is automated. A single individual, usually part-time, can run it.<br />
 <br />
<strong>4. It minimizes the need for additional waste treatment procedures in the environment:</strong><br />
 <br />
The machine technology can compost organic waste without using a landfill, incineration, or any other compost treatment method.<br />
 <br />
<strong>5. It is capable of composting all sorts of organic waste:</strong><br />
 <br />
Any organic waste may be converted into high-quality compost manure using the machine. Composting is widely used to dispose of food waste such as vegetables, non-vegetables, eggs, fish, crab, small bones, fruit and vegetable peels, and leftover meals.<br />
 <br />
<strong>6. It has a low operational cost:</strong><br />
 <br />
Rent, inventory, insurance, research and development, payroll, and other operational expenditures are minimal. Hence a composting machine’s operating costs are low.<br />
 <br />
<strong>7. It takes up a small amount of floor space:</strong><br />
 <br />
Due to the apparent great effectiveness of its mechanical treatment equipment, the machine is generally compact, and it takes up less space than traditional composting methods.<br />
 <br />
<strong>8. It kills pathogens:</strong><br />
 <br />
Organic waste is pasteurized in a composting machine. The pasteurization procedure kills microorganisms and enhances the compost’s life span. This makes it safe to handle by humans.<br />
 <br />
<strong>9. It makes sterilization easier:</strong><br />
 <br />
Sterilization destroys, deactivates, or otherwise removes any kinds of life and other biological agents contained in the compost, including fungus, bacteria, viruses, and other biohazard species. Due to this, people are less likely to get infections when utilizing compost.<br />
 <br />
<strong>10. It is long-lasting:</strong><br />
 <br />
The machine is built with a stainless-steel tank with a 20-year lifespan. That is why it is durable.<br />
 <br />
<strong>11. It may be bought or rented:</strong><br />
 <br />
Those in need of an organic waste composting machine have various options for getting one. They have the option of purchasing, renting, or leasing.<br />
 <br />
<strong>12. It enhances safety:</strong><br />
 <br />
So, because the overload function machine comes to a halt in an overload, it does not leak waste or endanger the user.<br />
 <br />
<strong>13. It has an efficient power management system:</strong><br />
 <br />
There are indications for the organic waste composter for power mode, heater, and power conservation mode.<br />
 <br />
The compost machine&#8217;s safety is improved by its self-acting control system. It also makes the manner of operation more convenient.<br />
 <br />
The discovery of the food waste composting machine was a turning point in the search for waste treatment technologies that are both safe and ecologically beneficial. As more public and private businesses and people become aware of the machines’ benefits, they turn to them to recycle and convert their waste to ease landfill congestion.<br />
 <br />
Composting machine technology provides several advantages that have attracted the attention of many customers. The devices are quiet, have no unpleasant odor, donot attract rats, insects, flies, and compost waste indefinitely. The efficiency of their volume reduction is in the region of 80 to 90%.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>6 Negative Effects of Improper Waste Management</title>
		<link>http://www.tmkhb.net/2023/01/16/6-negative-effects-of-improper-waste-management/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2023 13:19:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Composter-News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.tmkhb.com/?p=3326</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The negative effects of improper waste management resul [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The negative effects of improper waste management result in an unpleasant appearance and have an impact on a country’s total economy. Also, oil spills and chemical leaching, which directly cause soil and water contamination, pose a significant hazard to animals that rely on the environment.<br />
 <br />
The following are some of the disastrous consequences of today’s inefficient waste management systems:<br />
 <br />
<strong>1) Contamination of the Soil</strong><br />
 <br />
In an ideal world, all of our plastic, glass, metal, and paper trash would be recycled with the help of a composter machine and organic waste converter machine. It then comes back to us as a renewable resource. Contamination happens when hazardous components are spilled and buried in the soil. As a result, we must be cautious in handling petroleum hydrocarbons, solvents, pesticides, heavy metals, and lead.<br />
 <br />
<strong>2) Contamination of Water</strong><br />
 <br />
Water is an excellent solvent since it can hold a lot of dissolved compounds. As a result, water gathers up pollutants as it moves through the system. It frequently contains dissolved things like chemicals and gases. Rainfall combines readily with poisonous liquid substances and seeps into water streams, eventually ending up in nearby bodies of water. As a result, contamination risks exist at the nearby fountain, ponds, lakes, and even drinking water taps.<br />
 <br />
<strong>3) Climate Change-Induced Extreme Weather</strong><br />
 <br />
To begin with, when trash decomposes, harmful greenhouse gases are released. This heat is trapped when it rises to the earth’s surface. Extreme weather reactions, such as storms and typhoons, are a result of this. What other factors influence us? Apart from temperature, the amount of precipitation in the air is also greatly affected. Everything is fair game right now, from acid rain to violent hail storms to global warming. This extends to other sectors, such as thermal and radioactive pollution.<br />
 <br />
<strong>4) Contamination of the Air</strong><br />
 <br />
A lot of it makes us feel hopeless since we can’t seem to make the required changes. We believe we can’t possibly consume any less. Even so, we can at least recycle it according to a precise routine. When paper and plastic are burnt at the dump, chemicals have emitted that collect and contribute to the ozone layer and harm the human population in the area. Methane gas contributes as well. Furthermore, with pollutants like dioxin in the air, it has been established that it is damaging our health.<br />
 <br />
<strong>5) Endangering Animal and Marine Life</strong><br />
 <br />
Despite severe attempts to prevent it, we continue to witness trash, raw or untreated sewage, and other waste dumped. Any animal or marine life that comes into touch with it is severely harmed. Algal blooms and clusters are unavoidable, contaminating and eventually suffocating marine life such as coral and fish. We’ve seen how fishing lines, cigarette butts, plastic bottles, and Styrofoam usage may kill millions of marine life each year, as Conservation International has detailed.<br />
 <br />
<strong>6) Human Damage</strong><br />
 <br />
Consider the vast majority of the world’s population, where no scientific waste management system exists. There may be a system in place, but there is no dumping area to be located. Consider the impact of landfill fires on the general public. Whether they come from the air or accumulate in our cellars, landfill gases have been linked to cancer, respiratory, and visibility issues, and the explosion of cans puts individuals in the immediate vicinity in danger.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>About Composting</title>
		<link>http://www.tmkhb.net/2023/01/10/about-composting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2023 07:13:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Composter-News]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.tmkhb.com/?p=3308</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Purpose of Composting   1. Eliminate waste feeling and  [&#8230;]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><strong>Purpose of Composting</strong><br />
 <br />
<strong>1. Eliminate waste feeling and make handling easier</strong><br />
 <br />
Organic waste, especially livestock manure, has dirty feelings like stinky and sticky and is not easy to handle. This is due to high moisture and going bad of organic matter.<br />
 <br />
It makes it easier to handle to reduce moisture and decomposing organic matter by composting.<br />
 <br />
<strong>2. Decomposition of organic matter</strong><br />
 <br />
When microorganisms decompose organic matter, they consume oxygen and generate carbon dioxide. When organic matter is decomposed in the soil, oxygen may be deficient, which may affect soil and crops. It is necessary to decompose some organic matter by composting.<br />
 <br />
<strong>3. Death and inactivation of pathogenic bacteria, parasitic eggs, weed seeds</strong><br />
 <br />
Fermentation heat is generated when organic matter is decomposed during the composting process. This high temperature kills pathogens, parasite eggs, and weed seeds or inactivates them.<br />
 <br />
<strong>4. Improve preservation</strong><br />
 <br />
Long-term preservation becomes possible by composting.<br />
												<img decoding="async" width="640" height="334" src="https://www.tmkhb.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/img_compo_purpose.png" alt="" loading="lazy" srcset="https://www.tmkhb.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/img_compo_purpose.png 640w, https://www.tmkhb.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/img_compo_purpose-300x157.png 300w, https://www.tmkhb.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/img_compo_purpose-500x261.png 500w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" /><br />
		<strong>Flow to Compost Organic Wastes</strong><br />
 <br />
Organic waste is waste derived from animals and plants. For example, livestock manure, solid waste produced from the manufacturing process of food such as vegetable residue, brewing residue, fermentation residue, and waste of fish and animals. Organic fertilizer is produced from organic waste by microorganisms. They decompose easily decomposable organic matter.<br />
 <br />
To speed up the process artificially is called composting and it is necessary to create an environment where microorganisms are easy to operate.<br />
In general, composting is decomposition by aerobic microorganisms and aerobic fermentation.<br />
												<img decoding="async" width="702" height="249" src="https://www.tmkhb.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/img_compo_flow.png" alt="" loading="lazy" srcset="https://www.tmkhb.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/img_compo_flow.png 702w, https://www.tmkhb.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/img_compo_flow-300x106.png 300w, https://www.tmkhb.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/img_compo_flow-500x177.png 500w" sizes="(max-width: 702px) 100vw, 702px" /><br />
		<strong>Conditions Necessary for Aerobic Fermentation</strong><br />
 <br />
Aerobic fermentation is carried out by the activity of aerobic microorganisms. It is important to create and maintain conditions where aerobic microorganisms can be active. Aerobic microorganisms need air to breathe.<br />
 <br />
Nutrient source for the activity of microorganisms is necessary. Moisture is also important. But breathability gets worse if moisture is too high and even if the moisture is too low, the growth of microorganisms is suppressed so appropriate moisture adjustment is also necessary. Microorganisms involved in composting are activated at an ambient temperature of 30 ° C or higher and temperatures of 60 ° C or more are necessary for killing or inactivating pathogens, parasite eggs, or weed seeds.<br />
 <br />
It is also related to the evaporation of moisture so it is required to control the temperature.<br />
												<img decoding="async" width="800" height="175" src="https://www.tmkhb.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/img_compo_term.png" alt="" loading="lazy" srcset="https://www.tmkhb.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/img_compo_term.png 800w, https://www.tmkhb.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/img_compo_term-300x66.png 300w, https://www.tmkhb.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/img_compo_term-768x168.png 768w, https://www.tmkhb.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/img_compo_term-500x109.png 500w" sizes="(max-width: 800px) 100vw, 800px" /><br />
		<strong>Aerobic Microorganisms</strong><br />
 <br />
Microorganisms for composting exist naturally in raw materials, air, livestock houses, etc.<br />
 <br />
<strong>Uniform Air Supply</strong><br />
 <br />
Air (oxygen) is essential for aerobic microorganisms necessary for fermentation.<br />
 <br />
Because aerobic microorganisms oxidize by decomposing organic matter using air, generates fermentation heat by oxidation reaction and promotes evaporation of moisture.<br />
 <br />
In the composting process, 「1. Air flowing」 in the raw material is an important point. Next, it is also important to 「2. Adjust proper moisture before composting treatment」「3. Continue proper airflow into raw materials」.<br />
 <br />
By regularly performing stirring and turning back, it makes uniform contact with the air and does not cause fermentation irregularity.<br />
 <br />
However, excessive stirring and turning down will lower the internal temperature and will slow down composting, so it is important to be proper.<strong>Nutrition Source</strong><br />
 <br />
There are two kinds of Organic substances. One is organic substances that are easily decomposed (easily decomposable organic substances) and another is organic substances that hardly decomposed (hardly decomposable organic substances). Most of the nutrient source of microorganisms is easily decomposable organic substances.<br />
 <br />
Livestock manure and others containing a lot of easily decomposable organic matter are rich in nutrients for microorganisms.<br />
												<img decoding="async" width="520" height="283" src="https://www.tmkhb.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/img_compo_term_01.png" alt="" loading="lazy" srcset="https://www.tmkhb.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/img_compo_term_01.png 520w, https://www.tmkhb.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/img_compo_term_01-300x163.png 300w, https://www.tmkhb.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/img_compo_term_01-500x272.png 500w" sizes="(max-width: 520px) 100vw, 520px" /><br />
												<img decoding="async" width="520" height="240" src="https://www.tmkhb.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/img_compo_term_02.png" alt="" loading="lazy" srcset="https://www.tmkhb.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/img_compo_term_02.png 520w, https://www.tmkhb.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/img_compo_term_02-300x138.png 300w, https://www.tmkhb.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/img_compo_term_02-500x231.png 500w" sizes="(max-width: 520px) 100vw, 520px" /><br />
		<strong>Appropriate Water Content</strong><br />
 <br />
When moisture is too high, breathability is going bad, and even if the moisture is too low, the growth of microorganisms is suppressed, so appropriate water content adjustment is necessary. By appropriately maintaining the moisture of the raw material to be composted, it will shorten the processing time.<strong>Appropriate Temperature</strong><br />
 <br />
Aerobic microorganisms oxidize by decomposing organic matter using air and fermentation heat by oxidation reaction occurs.<br />
 <br />
As aerobic fermentation is promoted, the internal temperature rises above 60 degrees. As a result, moisture evaporates, and pathogenic bacteria and weed seeds are killed and inactivated.<br />
 <br />
It is possible to maintain a stable fermentation condition by preventing the influence of the external environment and performing aeration at high temperatures.<br />
 <br />
<strong>What are the Merits of Using Compost?</strong><br />
 <br />
By properly using organic fertilizer, we can stably increase the production of crops by supplying nutrients to plants, improving the chemical, material, and biological of the soil, and increasing soil productivity.<br />
 <br />
Compost is a kind of fertilizer for both plants and soil.<br />
 <br />
Chemical fertilizers are excellent as fertilizer components, but microorganisms in the soil are killed as organic matter is not supplied. When soil cultivation to make crumb structures by microorganisms is stopped, soil productivity declines, the plants become weak against diseases and pests, and need to use fungicides and insecticides.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
